Finding Aid for the Raymond Chandler Papers, 1930-1959
UCLA Library Special Collections
Raymond Chandler Papers,
1930-1959
638
Chandler, Raymond, 1888-1959
13 boxes (6.5 linear ft.) 1 oversize box
Raymond Thornton Chandler (1888-1959) published his first novel, The Big Sleep, to great success in 1939 and began writing screenplays in 1944. The collection consists of correspondence, books, photographs, speeches, and literary manuscripts by Raymond Chandler.
University of California, Los Angeles. Library Special Collections. Los Angeles, California 90095-1575
Administrative Information
Restrictions on Access
COLLECTION STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF: Advance notice required for access.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Raymond Chandler, 1954-1958.
Gift of James Sandoe, 1961.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 964180
Biography
Born Raymond Thornton Chandler in Chicago on July 23, 1888; studied at Dulwich College, London, and privately in France and Germany; began career as contributor of verse, essays, book reviews and special articles to daily and weekly papers in London, 1909; served with Canadian Expeditionary Force and R.A.F. during World War I; afterwards, returned to U.S. to become an officer in various independent oil corporations; began writing fiction contributions to magazines in 1933; published his first novel, The Big Sleep, to great success in 1939, followed by Farewell, My Lovely (1940), The Long Good-Bye (1954) and others; began writing and mostly co-writing screenplays in 1944; his best known screenplay is Double Indemnity, based on James Cain's novel; died in La Jolla, California, March 26, 1959.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of correspondence, books, photographs, speeches, and literary manuscripts by Raymond Chandler. Includes manuscripts for The Little Sister, The Long Good-Bye, Playback and the Poodle Springs Story. Also includes Billy Wilder's copy of the screenplay of Double Indemnity and various writings about and interviews with Chandler.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Photographs (Box 1).
Correspondence (Boxes 1-2).
Writings by Chandler (Boxes 2-8,12-13).
Screenplays by Chandler (Boxes 8-9; 13).
Writings about Chandler (Boxes 9-12).
Correspondence with James Sandoe (Box 1).
Books by and about Raymond Chandler, including translations in various languages (Boxes 15-58).
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Chandler, Raymond, 1888-1959--Archives.; Authors, American--20th century--Archival resources.; Screenwriters--United States--Archival resources.
Genres and Forms of Material
Manuscripts for publication.; Mystery and detective fiction.
Container List
- Photographs
  - Cissy Chandler. Los Angeles., (6.75 × 8.75”). (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Photograph by J.W. Siefert.
    Gift of Ed Smith [nephew of Cissy and Raymond Chandler], 1989.
  - Cissy Chandler as a young woman. n.p., (3.875” - Photograph, mounted on board, has been cut into a circle). (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Photographer unknown.
    Gift of Ed Smith, 1989.
  - Lavinia Smith [sister of Cissy Chandler]. New York., (2 items: 4.33 × 4.75” and 4 × 5.5”). (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Photograph by Davis & Sanford.
    With another copy cut into an oval.
  - Lavinia Smith [sister of Cissy Chandler]. New York., (6 × 7.75”). (Box 1, Folder 4)
    “Vinnie at 16” by Davis & Sanford.
  - Raymond Chandler in a World War I Canadian army uniform. Seaford., (2 items: 3.875 × 5.75” and 8 × 10” copy - With black and white copy print). (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Portrait by Mina Whiting.
    Gift of Mrs. Helga Greene, January 1960.
  - Raymond Chandler and other writers from Black Mask. [Los Angeles?]., January 11, 1936; (3 items: 8 × 10”). (Box 1, Folder 6)
    The original photograph, mounted on a linen tablecloth and signed by the authors present, is in the Joseph Shaw papers (collection 2052), box 6.
  - Raymond Chandler and Billy Wilder. [Hollywood]., 1944; (8 × 10”). (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Taken on the set of “Double Indemnity.”
    11 × 14” print is in oversize box 14, folder 3.
  - Raymond Chandler and Taki. La Jolla., September 4, 1948; (8 × 10”). (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Inscribed to James Sandoe, photograph by John Engstead. “Dear Sandoe: I had to hold Taki's tail to keep it still. Raymond Chandler, La Jolla 9/4/48.”
  - Raymond Chandler. La Jolla., February 1958; (3.25 × 4.25” and 8 × 10” - With 2 [8 × 10”] copy prints). (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Chandler holding a glass, photograph by Vincent Fracasse.
  - Raymond Chandler. La Jolla., February 1958; (3 × 5”). (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Chandler putting on gloves, photograph by Vincent Fracasse.
  - Raymond Chandler. London., 1958; (2 items, 3.5 × 4.5” and 8 × 10” - 8 × 10” is copy print). (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Raymond Chandler and Billy Wilder. [Hollywood]., 1944; (11 × 14”). (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Correspondence
  - Personal
    - Raymond Chandler - University of California, Los Angeles. La Jolla., March 18, 1952; (1 leaf). (Box 1, Folder 18)
      Letter to Lawrence Clark Powell.
    - Ralph Lyon, Jr. - Raymond Chandler. Los Angeles., March 18, 1955; (1 leaf). (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Raymond Chandler - Lawrence Clark Powell. La Jolla., December 3, 1956; (1 leaf). (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Raymond Chandler - Arthur Lovell. La Jolla., circa 1950 and 1954; (8 items). (Box 2, Folder 26)
      - circa 1954., (1 leaf). (Box 2, Folder 26)
      - August 26, 1954., (1 leaf). (Box 2, Folder 26)
      - July 5, 1954., (1 postcard). (Box 2, Folder 26)
      - May 31, 1954., ([2pp.] - postcard). (Box 2, Folder 26)
      - February 9, 1954., (1 leaf). (Box 2, Folder 26)
      - December 19, 1950., (1 leaf). (Box 2, Folder 26)
      - December 6, 1950., (1 leaf). (Box 2, Folder 26)
        With Lovell's holograph draft reply on the verso.
      - November 29, 1950., (1 leaf). (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Raymond Chandler - Philip Durham. La Jolla., September 5, 1958; (1 leaf). (Box 2, Folder 28)
      re reprinting Chandler's article “The simple art of murder.”
    - Raymond Chandler - Robert Campigny. La Jolla., February 7, 1958; (1 leaf). (Box 2, Folder 29)
      The letter is in French. An English translation is with it.
  - Correspondence About Raymond Chandler
    - James Sandoe to Orville Prescott and Robert Van Gelder. [Boulder]., July 30, 1943; (1 leaf [2pp.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Orville Prescott to James Sandoe. New York., August 3, 1943; (Typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - James Sandoe to Bernard Smith. Boulder., December 29, 1943; (1 leaf, typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Sydney A. Sanders to James Sandoe. New York., April 26, 1945; (1 leaf [1p.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - James Sandoe to “Sanders.” Boulder., April 30, 1945; (1 leaf [1p.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Bernard Smith, Alfred A. Knopf, Incorporated to James Sandoe. New York., 1943 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - May 19, 1943., (1 leaf, typescript signed on verso). (Box 1, Folder 12)
        re letters to Van Gelder, Prescott, Cupp and Gannett.
        [Also,] Sandoe's reply, July 29, 1943 (typescript carbon).
      - August 2, 1943., (Typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - August 10, 1943., (Typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - January 3, 1944., (Typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - James Sandoe to “Miss Dunham.” Boulder., August 23, 1947; (1 leaf [1p.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence Between Raymond Chandler and James Sandoe
    - Raymond Chandler to James Sandoe. v.p., 1944-1954 (Box 1, Folder 13, 17)
      - n.p., November 8, 1946; (1 leaf [1p.], typescript carbon, signed). (Box 1, Folder 13)
        With typescript note.
      - London., October 7, 1952; (1 leaf [1p.] - Autograph letter signed, postcard). (Box 1, Folder 17)
        Postmarked 7 October 1952.
    - Raymond Chandler to James Sandoe. Hollywood., 1944-1946 (Box 1, Folder 12-13)
      - January 26, 1944., (2 leaves [2pp.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 12)
        Paramount Pictures Incorporated letterhead.
        Signed “Ray Chandler.” With discussion of comparison with James Cain.
      - April 11, 1944., (Typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - January 15, 1945., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 12)
        With pencil notes by James Sandoe[?].
      - January 26, 1945., (2 leaves [2pp.], typescript signed, Signed “Ray.”). (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - February 10, 1945., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - April 4, 1945., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - July 3, 1946., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Raymond Chandler to James Sandoe. Los Angeles, 1944-1946 (Box 1, Folder 12-13)
      - Postmark is October 2, 1944 (Card is not dated)., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript postcard). (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - December 16, 1944., (1 leaf, typescript and typescript signature). (Box 1, Folder 12)
        Chandler's address: 6520 Drexel Avenue, Los Angeles 36.
      - August 18, 1945., (1 leaf [2pp.], typescript). (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - August 28, 1945., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - September 9, 1945., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - November 9, 1945., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript). (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - November 28, 1945., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript postcard). (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - May 30, 1946., (2 leaves [2pp.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - June 17, 1946., (3 leaves [3pp.], typescript). (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Raymond Chandler to James Sandoe. La Jolla., 1946-1954 (Box 1, Folder 13-17)
      - October 2, 1946., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - October 17, 1946., (1 leaf [2pp.], typescript with holograph corrections). (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - December 6, 1946., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - December 12, 1946., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - January 21, 1947., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - February 7, 1947., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - March 8, 1947., (2 leaves [2pp.], typescript). (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - March 18, 1947., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript postcard). (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - May 3, 1947., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - June 7, 1947., (2 leaves [2pp.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - June 23, 1947., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - July 14, 1947., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript postcard). (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - July 28, 1947., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - August 10, 1947., (2 leaves [2pp.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - August 21, 1947., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript with holograph corrections). (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - September 14, 1947., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript). (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - October 2, 1947., (5 leaves [5pp.] - typescript with holograph corrections). (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - October 13, 1947., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript postcard). (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - November 7, 1947., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript). (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - n.p., December 21, 1947.; (1 leaf [1p.], typescript postcard). (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - January 27, 1948., (3 leaves [3pp.], typescript). (Box 1, Folder 14)
        “Dictated by not signed by Raymond Chandler. mo.”
      - February 1, 1948., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript with holograph note postcard). (Box 1, Folder 14)
        Postmarked February 1 or 11[?]
      - February 7, 1948., (1 leaf [1p.], telegram). (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - February 26, 1948., (2 leaves [2pp.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - February 27, 1948., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - March 1, 1948., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript). (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - March 18, 1948., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - April 1, 1948., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript postcard). (Box 1, Folder 14)
        Chandler has noted All Fools Day.
        Postmarked April 2.
      - April 5, 1948., (2 leaves [2pp.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - April 16, 1948., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - May 12, 1948., (2 leaves [2pp.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - August 9, 1948., (2 leaves [2pp.], typescript). (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - August 30, 1948., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript postcard). (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - September 23, 1948., (2 leaves [2pp.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - October 4, 1948., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript). (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - October 11, 1948., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - October 12, 1948., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript signed postcard). (Box 1, Folder 14)
        Postmarked 13 October 1948.
      - October 17, 1948., (2 leaves [2pp.], typescript with holograph corrections). (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - October 24, 1948., (2 leaves [2pp.], typescript). (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - November 18, 1948., (2 leaves [3pp.], typescript with holograph corrrections). (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - December 6, 1948., (3 leaves [3pp.], typescript with holograph corrections). (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - n.d.., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript postcard). (Box 1, Folder 14)
        Postmarked December 8, 1948.
      - December 21, 1948., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript postcard). (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - December 15, 1948., (2 leaves [2pp.], typescript signed with holograph corrections). (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - December 22, 1948., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript signed with holograph corrections). (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - December 30, 1948., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript with holograph corrections). (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - January 13, 1949., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript). (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - January 24, 1949., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript). (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - January 25, 1949., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript postcard). (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - February 25, 1949., (2 leaves [2pp.], typescript with holograph corrections). (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - March 4, 1949., (1 leaf [2pp.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - March 26, 1949., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript postcard). (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - April 10, 1949., (2 leaves [2pp.], typescript with holograph corrections). (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - April 14, 1949., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - May 3, 1949., (3 leaves [3pp.], typescript with holograph corrections). (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - May 12, 1949., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - May 14, 1949., (2 leaves [2pp.], typescript). (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - May 20, 1949., (2 leaves [2pp.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - May 23, 1949., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - June 2, 1949., (2 leaves [2pp.], typescript). (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - June 16, 1949., (3 leaves [3pp.], typescript with holograph corrections). (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - August 10, 1949., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript signed postcard). (Box 1, Folder 15)
        Postmarked August 11, 1949.
      - August 15, 1949., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - August 22, 1949., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript with holograph corrections postcard). (Box 1, Folder 15)
        Postmarked 22 August 1949.
      - September 14, 1949., (2 leaves [2pp.], typescript signed with holograph corrections). (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - September 20, 1949., (2 leaves [2pp.], typescript signed with holograph corrections). (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - October 14, 1949., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - November 6, 1949., (2 leaves [2pp.], typescript with holograph corrections). (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - November 19, 1949., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript). (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - November 21, 1949., (3 leaves [3pp.], typescript with holograph corrections). (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - December 4, 1949., (1 leaf [2pp.], typescript with holograph corrections). (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - December 16, 1949., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript signed with holograph corrections). (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - December 28, 1949., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript signed with holograph corrections). (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - January 25, 1950., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript). (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - October 9, 1950., (2 leaves [2pp.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - December 7, 1950., (2 leaves [2pp.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - January 10, 1951., (3 leaves [3pp.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - February 20, 1951., (3 leaves [3pp.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - February 26, 1951., (2 leaves [2pp.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - March 6, 1951., (3 leaves [3pp.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - March 31, 1951., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - September 25, 1951., (2 leaves [2pp.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - October 31, 1951., (2 leaves [2pp.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - December 27, 1951., (2 leaves [2pp.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - January 10, 1952., (1 leaf [1p.], Telegram). (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - January 10, 1952., (2 leaves [2pp.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - April 14, 1952., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - July 30, 1952., (3 leaves [3pp.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - August 11, 1952., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - January 6, 1953., (2 leaves [2pp.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - February 4, 1953., (3 leaves [3pp.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - March 16, 1953., (4 leaves [4pp.] with 1 envelope - typescript with holograph corrections). (Box 1, Folder 17)
        p.1 is a postcard followed by 3 typescript pages and an envelope addressed in Chandler's.
      - March 26, 1954., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript signed postcard). (Box 1, Folder 17)
        Postmarked 27 March 1954.
      - April 8, 1954., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript with holograph corrections, postcard). (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - May 26, 1954., (2 leaves [2pp.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - James Sandoe to Raymond Chandler. Boulder., 1944-1954 (Box 1, Folder 12-17)
      - January 8, 1944., (1 leaf [2pp.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - January 12, 1944., (1 leaf [2pp.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - January 22, 1945., (1 leaf [2pp.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - January 23, 1945., (1 leaf [2pp.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - April 11, 1945., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - August 12, 1945., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - August 22, 1945., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - August 23, 1945., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - August 31, 1945., (1 leaf [2pp.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - September 16, 1945., (1 leaf [2pp.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - January 9, 1946., (1 leaf [2pp.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - February 3, 1946., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - May 7, 1946., (1 leaf [2pp.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - June 6, 1946., (1 leaf [2pp.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - July 5, 1946., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - September, 25, 1946., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - October 14, 1946., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - October 19, 1946., (1 leaf [2pp.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - February 19, 1947., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - March 24, 1947., (1 leaf [2pp.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - April 29, 1947., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - June 11, 1947., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - July 15, 1947., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - July 17, 1947., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - August 5, 1947., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - August 14, 1947., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - September 25, 1947., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - November 3, 1947., (1 leaf [2pp.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - November 12, 1947., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - December 16, 1947., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - February 3, 1948., (1 leaf [2pp.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - February 8, 1948., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - March 1, 1948., (1 leaf [2pp.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - March 22, 1948., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - April 19, 1948., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - June 16, 1948., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - July 21, 1948., (1 leaf [2pp.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - September 19, 1948., (1 leaf [2pp.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - October 3, 1948., (1 leaf [2pp.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - October 13/14, 1948., (1 leaf [2pp.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - October 30, 1948., (1 leaf [2pp.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - December 1, 1948., (1 leaf [2pp.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - December 10, 1948., (1 leaf [2pp.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - December 26, 1948., (1 leaf [2pp.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - January 5, 1949., (1 leaf [2pp.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - January 10, 1949., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - January 16, 1949., (1 leaf [2pp.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - January 19, 1949., (1 leaf [2pp.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - January 31, 1949., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - March 20, 1949., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - April 30, 1949., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - May 6, 1949., (1 leaf [2pp.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - May 17, 1949., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript carbon, carbon folded[?]). (Box 1, Folder 15)
        Lower left corner: Part of the text is missing.
      - May 29, 1949., (1 leaf [2pp.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - June 9, 1949., (1 leaf [2pp.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - August 30, 1949., (1 leaf [2pp.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - September 16, 1949., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - September 25, 1949., (1 leaf [2pp.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - October 31/November 1, 1949., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - November 13, 1949., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - December 11, 1949., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - [1949 ?]., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 15)
        Lacking first page. “49?” is pencilled in the upper right corner in an unidentified hand.
      - January 30, 1950., (1 leaf [1p.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - November 25, 1950., (1 leaf [2pp.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - January 1, 1951., (1 leaf [2pp.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 16)